so let's go to this story I want you to
turn with me to the Book of Jonah and
we're going to go to Jonah chapter 1 the
Book of Jonah chapter 1 Jonah chapter 1
the Bible says now the word of the Lord
came unto Jonah the son of amitayus
saying arise go to Nineveh that great
city and cry against it for their
wickedness is come up before me now ask
you a question how wicked do you think
the city of Nineveh was pretty bad
pretty bad that God says to Jonah I need
you to go and I need you to warn this
city so we might think of Nineveh as a
wicked or sinful City and God has called
Jonah to go and preach against this city
Nasr question how do you think God feels
about Nineveh saying in not very good
all right concerned
sad disconnected does God is Nineveh and
evil and adulterous generation does God
love that evil and adulterous generation
how do we know God loves that evil and
adulterous generation because he sends
Jonah to that evil and adulterous
generation because he wants that evil
and adulterous generation to want to
repent for God so loved the world right
that He gave His only begotten Son so we
know how God feels about this even
though there and there are evil and
adulterous generation God is about to
send Jonah verse 3 but Jonah Roza to
flee on to Tarshish from the presence of
the Lord and went down to Joppa and he
found the ship going to Tarshish so he
paid the fare thereof and went down into
it to go with them on to Tarshish from
the presence of the Lord now Jonah
decided that he is not going to obey God
I have a question for you why I'm here
in a hole
why does jonah decide i'm not even going
to go to nineveh all right let me let me
ask you this way let's say that you know
you lived outside of the Bay Area and
then someone said to you hey we're gonna
pay you to go evangelize the Bay Area
many of you might say that Bay Area are
you serious
that area is so secular that area is is
so far from having God on their minds
all they're about is money like they're
not going to hear my message do you
think so what's going through Jonah's
mind this city is so wicked that they
will not hear me if I were to go it's as
if Jonah has written off this wicked
city and so you know the story Jonah
goes down into the ship but the Bible
says in verse 4 but the Lord sent out a
great wind into the sea and there was a
mighty tempest in the sea so that the
ship was like to be broken and the
Mariners were afraid and and and tried
every man unto his operative criteria
and was God and cast forth the wares
that were in the ship into the sea to
lighten it of them but Jonah was gone
down into the sides of the ship and he
lay and was fast asleep and you know the
story right these men are terrified
because this storm has come by the way
God brought the storm God brought this
stone because Jonah was going against
the will of God and so God brings this
mighty wind and the people start start
crying out to their gods got their gods
are not answering and then they find
Jonah asleep in the bottom of the ship
and they go to him and they say who are
you and Jonah tells them who he is and
then Jonah says listen this is my fault
this is happening because of me and they
say to Jonah well what
we do and I want you to check this out
jump down with me to verse 16 verse
rather verse verse 11 they said unto Him
what shall we do unto thee that the sea
may be calm unto us and this for the sea
wrought and was tempestuous and he
summoned to them take me up and cast me
forth into the sea so shall the sea be
common to you for I know that from my
sake this great tempest is upon you
verse 16 then the men feared or verse 15
so they took up Jonah and cast him forth
into the sea and the sea ceased from her
raging then the men feared the Lord
exceedingly and offered a sacrifice unto
the Lord and made vows now the Lord had
prepared a great fish to swallow up
Jonah and Jonah was in the belly of the
fish three days and what three nights
Jonah is thrown overboard and as soon as
he is thrown overboard
something happens tell me what happens
the seas are calm let me speak to you
for a moment
you see Jonah being thrown overboard
would have ensured his what his his
death this was a raging storm not a
question for you how many of you've ever
experienced a raging storm in your life
how many of you know what it's like to
go through those raging storms listen
carefully when Jonah was thrown
overboard remember Jesus said of himself
that Jonah was a type of himself
I want to suggest to you that Jesus's
death brings the calm to our storms
Jesus when he died his death let me let
me say this way many of us ride the
storm of life without Direction fearful
and when Jesus comes into the life when
we accept his death burial and
resurrection that has power to calm the
storms I can look back at my life before
Jesus entered and it was a stormy life
it was a it was a stormy path but once I
accepted Christ into my life guess what
his death burial and resurrection calm
the storms how many of you remember the
story where Jesus is on the ship with
the disciples and he is sleeping and
remember how the Bible says this storm
came upon the waters and and they were
all terrified just like the story of
Jonah and they go and wake Jesus up they
say do you not care that we perish and
Jesus looks like when he says o ye of
what little faith and he stands up and
he says peace be still peace be still
and beloved when he said those words the
waters were calmed listen to me the
storms of life can be totally
overwhelming but Jesus
says I am come listen check us out guys
Jonah went on a journey is that right
he worked not at first his journey was
away from Nineveh but we're going to see
the story that God eventually convinces
Jonah that his journey should be towards
Nineveh praise God that Jesus did not
need to be convinced to come to us he
did not run away from the will of God as
Jonah did nonetheless he uses Jonah as a
type of himself the death of Jesus calms
the storms that we're in Jesus says come
unto me all ye that labor and are heavy
laden and I will give you what rest
Psalm 107 verse 28 says this then they
cried to the Lord in their trouble and
he breathed them out of their distress
is he maketh the storm a calm so that
the waves thereof are still then are
they glad because they be quiet so he
bringing them unto their desired haven
Jesus is a master of calming the storms
in John 14 verse 27 jesus said peace I
leave with you my peace I give unto you
not as the world giveth give I unto you
let not your heart be troubled neither
let it be afraid Jesus is telling us
listen despite the storms going around
you know that because I came and died
for you that I will carry you safely
through the storm this is what Jesus
came to do so Jonah is swallowed up by
this fish in Jonah chapter 2 Jonah
chapter 2 verse 10 after Jonah spends
three days in the belly of this fish the
Bible says in the Lord spake unto the
fish and it vomited out Jonah unto the
dry land three days Jonah spent
in the belly of this fish Jonah chapter
3 verse 1 and the word of the Lord came
unto Jonah the second time saying arise
go unto Nineveh that great city and
preach unto it the preaching that I bid
thee so Jonah arose and went onto
Nineveh according to the word of the
Lord
now Nineveh was an exceeding great city
of three day's journey and Jonah began
to enter into the city a day's journey
and he cried and said yet forty days and
Nineveh shall be overthrown let me ask
you a question do you think Jonah just
had a rough three days do you think it
was a pretty pretty rough three days
the Bible says after these three days
God called this this fish to vomit Jonah
out so Jonah
rises up out of the water
now I want you to think about this the
men that had thrown him over believe
that he was one that he was dead
he is down there underwater for how many
days three days and then he is root he
is brought up out of the water and
listen carefully the Bible says that he
spoke among them that 40 days the city
would be overthrown let me ask you a
question does that picture look familiar
to you do you remember that Jesus Christ
who himself was dead buried and
resurrected on the third day appeared
among his people how many days 40 days
40 days and I want you to understand his
love you see this three day journey of
Jonah to Nineveh to the wicked city was
a treacherous journey and yet Jonah
because of his experience with God was
willing to take it let me ask you a
question was Jesus
his journey to the grave a treacherous
journey yeah do you think it was a
journey that none of us ourselves would
want to go through do you look at his
trial just before his death burial and
resurrection and seeing what Jesus went
through on the cross do you think that
that journey was something that no other
human being has ever experienced and yet
beloved in Jesus's mind the journey was
worth it the journey was worth it three
days journey and it was worth it why
because God so what loved the world that
He gave His only begotten Son the
journey was worth it